Software Developer in Tests

Software engineer with 10 years of experience, primarily as a QAE and SDET. Proven ability to design, develop, and implement test automation, test architecture, test management, and continuous integration solutions. Familiar with Agile software development and the software development life cycle.

Skills

- Frontend Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React
- Backend Technologies: Node.js, Nest.js, Ruby, bash
- · Tools: Git, NPM
- E2E testing: Playwright, Cypress, Selenium, WebdriverIO, Cucumber, Postman
- Performance testing: JMeter, Gatling, k6
- CI: Drone, GitHub Actions, Jenkins
- Cloud: AWS, Terraform, localstack
- Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes
- Databases: MongoDB, DynamoDB
- · Observability: AWS Cloud watch, New Relic, Pagerduty, Loz.io, Splunk

Certification

ISTQB - Foundation level

Work experience

Software Developer in Tests at Dazn (Amsterdam, Netherlands)

2019 - 2023 (November)

DAZN is a global sports streaming service that offers live and on-demand content.

- Launched and maintained the Sports Logos Manager service, which enables DAZN to support high demand for sports logos
 across the platform. The service is integrated with multiple front-end chapters, and it is highly scalable and distributed across
 multiple regions. It solves the problem of keeping competition logos up to date with minimal editor effort, ensuring that logo
 images are always resilient.
- Developed a test solution using LocalStack to eliminate the need for AWS resources (saving money) and simulate concurrent users.
- · Incorporated performance testing into the software development life cycle to detect performance regressions in each release.
- . Developed GitHub workflows to automate deployments and package releases.
- Developed front-end test automation solutions using Playwright and Cypress.
- Developed a backend test automation using nest.js, jest and docker.

QAE at ESAILORS (Hamburg, Germany)

2017 - 2019

Lotto24 is the leading German lottery provider on the Internet.

- Working primarily supporting backend microservices.
- Create and maintain automated tests framework using groovy and selenium.
- Create a test framework to validate emails across all platform.
- · Define test strategy.
- Maintain and create pipelines workflows in Jenkins.
- Analysis test reports.
- Create test stories in a scrum environment.

QAE at E.NEAR (Lisbon, Portugal)

2015 - 2017

E.Near is a software development company that provides nearshore services to clients in Europe

- Define test case
- Report bugs
- Create and maintain workflows in Jenkins
- Analysis test reports
- Maintenance QA environment (AWS instance)
- Create scripts (ruby , bash)

QAE at AFRICA INTERNET GROUP (Porto, Portugal)

2014 - 2015

Jumia is the leading pan-African e-commerce platform.

Automate the regression test suite using selenium, cucumber and Ruby

Software tester at FARFETCH (Porto, Portugal)

2013 - 2014

Farfetch is an online luxury fashion retail platform.

- Create and maintain automated tests integrations(rest API framework) and functional(selenium) tests
- Manual tests

Education

• Universidade de trás-os-montes e alto douro (UTAD) - Technology, Information and Communication

Contact Information

- Email: eterra1@hotmail.com
- LinkedIn: LinkedIn Profile
- PDF: [Download PDF](PDF.)